okay this is Aaron and Sammy training
session number seven this was a fairly
quick workout uh we start off with front
squats this is Aaron look at those knees
uh this every lifter has certain things
you you need to tell them you need to
cue them to make them be aware of with
Aaron it's your knee valgus and it's
getting way better you see that these
knees don't move out much uh that's 95
lbs now this is 105 again she has great
form here I was happy with this
Aaron is almost as strong with uh front
squatting as she has regular
squatting
um and that's that's 105 and then this
is 115 this is her previous one rep max
she ends up getting two reps knes come
in a little there but second rep looks a
little better um but yeah that's two
reps with their previous one rep max so
I was very happy with that that's a
PR uh this is Sumo dead
135 uh just like five weeks ago Aaron
was struggling with this weight she
could barely do it you see this she just
flies up looks like she could get that
for 10 reps if she
wanted um and now here's Sammy with
front squats I told Sammy uh to do three
reps and she did four like a
rebel
um form looks pretty
good Sammy does WID stance squats with
everything even front squats okay this
is 155
uh the weight is flying up looks
great uh three
reps now here's Sammy with
um back position looks good Samy has has
to uh work on Butt Wink that's her um
you know her thing we have to cue with
and make sure she doesn't let her low
back round when she does
things um where is it Aaron doesn't have
to worry about that this is 175 and
Aaron gets three reps which so her
previous uh no her one rep max is 185 so
she got two reps or sorry three reps
with 175 now here's Samy this is 175 and
watch this third rep here she loses it
in rounds that was bad good dep that's
Sammy wasn't concentrating there and
it's very very important to concentrate
um you know that's how injuries
happen um so Sammy kind of had an off
day but she made up for it the next
training session okay here's uh Aaron
with goblet squats I love this exercise
for her because she H she tends to cave
in at the knees this exercise makes her
keep those knees out see how the elbows
have to travel in this is 50 lbs and she
gets 12 reps this is a great exercise
for her I just gave her one set and now
here's Sammy 185 I told her make sure
that low back X doesn't lose its Arch
she got it that's a Max front squat for
her okay here's Sammy with 155 PB
deadlift looking better uh and uh you
see here she falls backwards there Sammy
had an off day um but it's okay these
these off days happen from time to time
especially you know that for people who
haven't been training for very long and
over time you get really good at your
training and here's Aaron with kettle
bell deadlifts you can see she got a
little squirly there I should have just
not had her touch the ground with him it
was the rebound off the floor that was
making her squirly but you know as a
trainer you pay attention to these
things and you learn what to do
different next time around okay here's
uh Samy Sumo Deads that was 185 and now
this is
205 uh Samy's so hip dominant you
know there I I'm using my phone too I'm
do using two I try to film video clips
for in Instagram too so Sammy gets three
reps with
205 or no that's 225 so that's tying her
previous record with better form so to
me that's a PR when you tie a a a
previous record but you use better form
that's a PR okay we used a higher bench
this time because the bench was being
used so this is hip thrust with a higher
bench Aaron didn't like it as much she
felt it a little more in her hamstrings
and not her
glutes so uh but this is a high I said
we're just going to do uh two sets of
really High Reps so here Aaron gets 30
reps here which is great because she
used to get this for 10 reps
um and so
uh yep she felt that set a lot in her
hamstrings the next set she felt more in
her glutes and here's Sammy this is
135 uh this is a piece of cake for Sammy
here she gets in her groove and just
starts
motoring um and she ends up getting 30
reps or so what I love about you know
Sammy has such long
femurs you know squatting and
deadlifting she's a very strong squatter
and deadlifter as you can see but it's
not the most coordinated lift for her
but hip thrust it's so stable you know
she's not going anywhere so this lets
her Express her maximum Glu power when
she does hip thrust because she's not
limited in coordination or
stability okay this is 185
uh and I believe Aaron gets like 11 or
so or 12 or something but she felt this
set more in her glutes than her last set
which she felt mostly in her hings but
this is too high of a bench needs to be
lower again as a trainer you learn these
things I won't use this bench again
um sometimes Aaron tends to skimp on her
range of motion on these I have to
remind her to go up all the way
where Samy is usually very good at going
up all the way uh Sammy has incredible
end range glute strength she's probably
the best I've ever trained at that U
this is
235 and I think Sammy gets 15
reps back uh last year I trained Sammy
for a bikini competition I think her
record was 245 for 20 so now she's at
230 235 for 15 so she's 10 lbs off in
five reps from her previous
alltime best
strength and now here's them doing band
seated H Productions you can see the
different styles here
uh Sammy likes her Sammy likes doing
them with her feet you know way out in
front of her and a more upright torso
whereas Aaron likes to lean in and have
more hip
flexion um and Sammy kind of starts in a
valgus position and goes to neutral
whereas kind of goes outside into a
varis position so it just shows you um
you know the different everyone's
different you got to Tinker with these
to feel what works for you best
um Now we move on to bench press
uh and close grip bench so I was very
happy with this close grip bench session
um this is Sammy with uh 75 had him do
three sets with 75 lbs
um talk your elbows more can't remember
exactly how many
reps the girls got but uh it's not easy
to be for you know you got to keep in
mind this is like week week um
four so it's you know what did you guys
look like your first month of bench
pressing you know now they they' lifted
before but never like powerlifting style
where you where the bar goes lower they
and it's almost harder to
ingrain proper movement patterns once
you've learned a certain way so for
those of us who bench like bodybuilders
with the bar you know our elbows flared
and the bar going higher up on the chest
it's very hard to learn how to tuck the
elbows and touch the bar Lower on the
chest but they do pretty good job here
um and it's funny some some reps you see
them struggle and kind of grind them out
and then some reps just fly out fly up
and that just go to show you how
important you know technique is in bar
position see like that one grinded it
out but then you'll see Aon get oh that
one she barely got but then it's weird
you'll see another rep go up faster like
that one get tight it's all that's why
you have to learn the exact place where
it's best for you to lower the bar and
keep your elbow flare at the right you
know the
perfect um positioning nice and that's
this
you know this is why experience and and
skill are so important in powerlifting
um but what I like is the girls are
using good uh their back position you
know they're keeping an
arch they're they're remaining stable
they're not uh flailing all around so
for month one of bench pressing them
super proud of them cuz their bench
their benches have both gone up a ton um
sometimes Aaron couple times on the
bench she's tried to squeeze out that
last repetition and I had to go rescue
her which you got to admire and someone
um so anyway that was uh session seven
uh except for some squirly reps I was
happy with this session um thanks for
watching